Register of the Millard Preston Goodfellow Papers, 1942-1967
Hoover Institution Archives
Millard Preston Goodfellow papers,
1941-1967
69085
Hoover Institution Archives
5 manuscript boxes, 2 envelopes (2.3 linear feet)
Correspondence, reports, printed matter, and photographs, relating to Office of Strategic Services operations in North Africa and the Far East during World War II, and to postwar reconstruction in Korea. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Goodfellow, Millard Preston, 1892-1973
Access
Collection open for research. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items, computer media, and digital files. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos, films, or digital files during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Biographical Note
1892, May 22 Born, Brooklyn, New York
1907 Reporter, Brooklyn Eagle
1932-1938 President, publisher, and trustee, Brooklyn Daily Eagle
1942-1946 Deputy Director, Office of Strategic Services (OSS)
1946 Political advisor to Commanding General, Korea
United States. Army--Officers.; United States. Office of Strategic Services.; Audiotapes.; Korea.; Reconstruction (1939-1951)--Korea.; United States--Armed Forces.; United States--Foreign relations.; World War, 1939-1945--Secret service.; World War, 1939-1945.
- CORRESPONDENCE, 1942-1967
  Arrangement Statement
  Arranged alphabetically by name of correspondent.
  - General, 1948-1949 (Box 1)
  - Unidentified, 1942-1964
  - Billinghurst, R. D. W., 1942
  - Bunce, Arthur C., 1950
  - Bunker, Laurence, 1951
  - Bush, Vannevar, 1942
  - Chae Byong Dock, 1950
  - Chang, John M., 1949-1950
  - Chang Kee Young, 1950-1954
  - Chesapeake & Potomac Telephone Co., 1944
  - Chey Soon Ju, 1949-1954
  - Chun Yong Soon, 1949
  - Coleman, Larry A., Jr., 1942
  - Cory, Ralph, 1942
  - Dolan, Mrs. Thomas, 1942
  - Donnelly, Dixon, 1966
  - Dubler, R. A., 1954
  - Eifler, Carl F., 1942
  - Engels, Lorraine E., 1949
  - Ensign-Bickford Co., 1942
  - Equitable Trust Co., 1951
  - Ferris, General B. G., 1943
  - Firth Sterling, Inc., 1954
  - Funk, Alvin L., 1949
  - Gellatly, J. A., 1942
  - Girdwood, D. R., 1954
  - Grombach, J. V., n.d.
  - Hahn Soon Kyo, 1942
  - Hodge, John R., 1946-1947
  - Hong Myung Ki, 1954
  - Hoyt, Palmer, Jr., 1946
  - Hull, Cordell, 1943
  - Hunter, J. H., 1942
  - Immigration and Naturalization Service, 1953
  - Johnson, President Lyndon, 1967
  - Joy, Jason S., 1948-1949
  - Kayfetz, Victor, 1954
  - Kennard, R. P., 1954
  - Kim, R. S., 1946
  - Kim, W. P., 1950
  - Koo Chang Seok, 1949
  - Kraemer, Elmer C., 1946
  - Kyong Ai Lee, 1951
  - Lady, Harold W., 1949
  - Latson, Almet R., Jr., 1942
  - Lemnitzer, L. L., 1959
  - Lewitt, Albert W., 1954
  - Limb, Ben C., 1950
  - Liu Chieh, 1942
  - Longwell, A. L., 1946
  - Luce, Henry R., 1947
  - Luckett, H. B., 1954
  - McCloy, John J., 1966
  - McDowell, C. S., 1953-1954
  - Morane, M. Robert, 1953
  - Myung Ki Hong, 1954
  - Namkoong, David Y., 1950
  - Neris International, Inc., 1954
  - Newmark, Howard, 1948
  - Oliver, Robert T., 1951
  - Pack Sang-Kyu, 1946
  - Pak, Ki Hyo, 1946
  - Pak Yung Chong, 1948
  - Pakistan Embassy, Washington, D.C., 1954
  - Pramoj, M. R. Seni, 1942
  - Price, Harry B., 1942
  - Pyun, Y. T., 1954
  - Remington Arms Co., 1942
  - Rhee, Francesca (Mrs. Syngman), 1950-1964
  - Rhee, Syngman, 1945-1965
  - Riggs National Bank, 1951
  - Roberts, Rankin, 1946
  - Rostow, Walt W., 1961-1967
  - Ryang, Dr. S. T., 1950-1951
  - Sae Sun Kim, 1950-1954
  - Shaffi, L., 1954 (Box 2)
  - Shepardson, Whitney H., 1960
  - Smith, Russell B., 1946
  - Smith, W. T., Jr., 1946
  - Solberg, Bob, 1941-1954
  - Staggers, John, 1953
  - Steck, Ernest E., 1946
  - Stilwell, Joseph W., 1945
  - Tolstoy, Beatrice, 1942
  - Tolstoy, Ilia, 1942-1943
  - United Nations, 1953
  - United States. Department of State. Passport Division, 1942
  - United States. Department of the Army, 1951
  - Upton, T. Graydon, 1954
  - Warlick, H. O., Jr., 1954
  - Warner, Langdon, 1949
  - Washington Post, 1947
  - Werner, A. P., 1942
  - West, Esther I., 1945
  - Williams, Justin, 1953-1954
  - Woo Pyung Kim, 1950
  - Wood, C. Tyler, 1953
  - Woolley, Herbert, 1948
  - Woonkyung, Nancy, 1953
  - Yau, C. F., 1949
  - Yim, Louise, 1946-1949
  - Yoo, Chang S., 1954
  - Yoon, Hogan, 1952
  - You Chan Yang, 1953
  - Young Han Choo, 1953
- SUBJECT FILE, 1942-1967
  Scope and Contents note
  Memoranda, reports, and printed material arranged alphabetically by title or subject.
  - Algeria (Box 2)
  - Baillie, Hugh
  - Balkan countries
  - Biographical material
  - Bishop, Max W.
  - China
  - Dalai Lama, Tibet
  - DeYoung, Henry C.
  - Gauss, Clarence
  - Grombach, John V.
  - Harris, Frederick Brown, 1947
  - Kim (Chief of Korean Air Force)
  - Knowland, William
  - Korea
    - General
      - Memoranda, reports
      - Newspaper clippings
      - Printed material
    - Ministry of Foreign Affairs (Box 3)
    - Rehabilitation and relief
    - Terrain handbook (U.S. Far East Command)
  - Korean-American Times
  - Korean Commission
  - Lattimore, Owen
  - Limb, Ben C.
  - MacArthur, General Douglas
  - Military District of Washington, D.C.
  - Miscellany
  - Mutual Defense Assistance Act of, 1949
  - National City Bank of New York
  - North Africa
  - North, Robert
  - Office of Strategic Services (OSS)
    - Correspondence
      - January-May 1942
      - June 1942-1945
    - Memoranda (Box 4)
      - 1941-March 1942
      - April 1942-May 1942
      - June-July 1942
      - August-December 1942
      - 1943-1944
  - Oliver, Kenneth A.
  - Press releases
  - Psychological warfare
  - Rhee, Francesca
  - Rhee, Syngman
  - Ryang, Soon Tai
  - Thailand
  - U.S. Department of State
  - U.S. War Department
  - Waller, Frederick
  - Van Item, James
  - War Department, Military Intelligence Division
- PHONOTAPES, 1967
  - Lecture to the Defense Intelligence School, Washington, D.C., November 17, 1967 (Box 5)
- SCRAPBOOK
  - Clippings and photos of Frederick Waller and others. (Box 5)
- AUDIO-VISUAL
  General note
  See Photo card catalog.
- DECLASSIFIED U.S. GOVERNMENT RECORDS, 1941-1946
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Available as PDF files. The PDF files are page images, so full-text search is not possible. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder by date of creation.
  - 2010 release of records, 1941-1946 (Reading room workstation)
  - 2011 September release of records, 1941-1946 (Box 5)
    Consists of British Military Attache, China, report on explosives, 1941, and radiogram from Korea, 1946
  - 2015 May release of records, 1946 (Box 5)